INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST

Solid technical background combined with exceptional skills in providing Helpdesk/user support with hardware, applications, peripherals and workstation maintenance/upgrades in complex multivendor environments. Strong expertise in a wide variety of databases, software systems and telecommunications networks, including all aspects of performance tuning. Integrates business requirements with the latest technologies to deliver cost-effective solutions. Swiftly comprehends the "big picture" and executes the boldest of organizational visions. Core competencies include:

- ♦ Secret Security Clearance
- ◆ Outstanding Communicator ◆
- Helpdesk Administration

- ◆ LAN/WAN Strategies
- ◆ Hardware/Software Support ◆
 - Network Optimization

- Information Assurance
- ♦ Innovative Problem Solver
- Excellent People Skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rapiscan Systems Kuwait *Field Service Specialist*

Jan 2017 - Feb 2021

- Contacts and coordinates with internal departments for parts as required ensuring optimal equipment operation.
- Acquaints customer personnel with the full capabilities of the equipment and/or systems for the immediate operational requirements.
- Advises customer of all equipment changes and authorized modifications.
- Prepares and submits trip reports which include results and recommendations for product improvement and site efficiency.
- Knowledge of complex mechanical systems, familiarity with test equipment; experience with High Voltage and X-ray producing equipment.
- Perform computer hardware and hard drive maintenance, install software upgrades, scripting for windows automation and editing batch files for improved compatibility between the computer and equipment interface.

Lockheed Martin Abu Dhabi UAE

Jun 2014 - Jan 2017

Information Systems Analyst

- Inspect servers and computers for any changes, unauthorized intrusions and problems that may have occurred overnight.
- Inspect shared network drives for unapproved applications, media, and files. Documentation and removal procedures are implemented if unapproved items are discovered.
- Verify whether any system errors have occurred. If errors are present, research the source of their origin(s) and cause(s), and develop an implementation and documentation plan for corrective actions.
- Enforced IA policy and annual required training of System Administrators.
- Perform initial/advanced client workstation diagnostics and troubleshooting of client workstations assigned to them.
- Provide proactive application assistance for office automation applications; perform workstation diagnostics and troubleshooting; assign, modify and delete passwords/user privileges.

Staff Tech Contracts CTR (Harbor UCLA Medical Center) Torrance, California Mar 2013 – May 2014 *PC Support Technician*

- Download/configure network software and hardware according to DHS policies and procedures.
- Clone Windows 7 & Windows XP PC from a standard image utilizing ZenNetworks.
- Upgrade existing systems by salvaging outdated PC equipment.
- Provides installation maintenance & technical support for roughly 25K PC's and 800 peripherals.
- Perform initial/advanced client workstation diagnostics and troubleshooting of client workstations assigned to them.
- Provided Level I/II technical support for PC/MAC LAN workstation end-users; developed, maintained and communicated standard hardware/software setup and configuration profiles.
- Utilize Footprint tracking software to track and complete work orders assigned to group.

VYKIN CORP, Thumrait, Oman *Client Support Admin*

Sep 2012 – Jan 2013

- Flawlessly perform equipment installation, peripherals connection, and all aspects of client-level software install/delete; ensure physical security of unit Air Force GIG components.
- Provide proactive application assistance for office automation applications; perform workstation diagnostics and troubleshooting; assign, modify and delete passwords/user privileges.
- Report security breaches and distribute security information; coordinate support issues with all appropriate agencies; notify the unit EC of any hardware relocation and equipment issues.
- Implement software patches, security fixes, and service releases; perform account and e-mail management; configure accounts and mailboxes; perform Directory Service support.

KFORCE (AEROSPACE), El Segundo, California *Customer Service Technician*

Feb 12 - Sep 12

- Installed and maintained 700+ computers and peripheral devices while providing support to 400+
- Provided "customer is always first" Helpdesk support with very few issues having to be escalated.
- Work with end users to solve software problems and tailor automation tools to their individual needs. Maintained base server integrity by authorizing access for computers and personnel utilizing Microsoft Active Directory security groups.
- Reports security incidents and formulates and applies corrective security procedures.
- Upgraded multiple training classrooms totaling more than 200 computers.

ROCKWELL COLLINS, Camp Leatherneck, Afghanistan *Help Desk Technician*

users and associated organizational accounts.

Dec 10 - Feb 12

- Key player on a Helpdesk team providing Level I/II technical support to 5K+ end users.
- Provided direct IT (Data/Phone) support for units supporting military operations in Afghanistan.
- Used Active Directory and Windows Servers to create user accounts, OU's and OMB's including clearing port security on NIPR, SIPR and CENTRIX utilizing PUTTY.
- Share-point Administrator, Updates, configures, and modify unit's share-point page.
- Help desk user/phone support for MS Windows XP/2000 OSs, MSOffice, XP and all standard DOD baseline software, and support of peripheral equipment - printers, fax, copier, and digital senders.
- Enforced IA policy and annual required training of System Administrators.
- Installed and troubleshot network and user hardware used by staff personnel.
- Assign, modify, and delete passwords and user privileges utilizing Active Directory.
- Implement client workstation software patches, security fixes, and service releases according to the local NCC instructions.

- Installed and maintained 700+ computers and peripheral devices while providing support to 400+ users and associated organizational accounts.
- Established/updated email accounts for NATO personnel at Camp Phoenix. Afghanistan.
- Utilized Remedy web based/software to track and modify phone/user/network issues.
- Led five Airmen in performance of Client Support Administrator duties with an emphasis on mentorship and positive motivation.
- Configured computers and peripheral devices to meet Yokota Air Base Japan duty requirements by troubleshooting and resolving all network issues.
- Designed the layout for one organization's SharePoint deployment.
- Implemented several Classified Message Incident measures by isolating and wiping the computers to successfully prevent numerous unauthorized disclosures.
- Provide software application assistance for commonly used office automation applications
 purchased from standard Air Force support contracts. Include support to standard wireless office
 automation devices.
- Promote user awareness concerning unauthorized or illegal use of computer hardware and software.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

TRIDENT UNIVERSITY INTERNATIONAL (TUI), Cypress, California

Master of Science, Information Systems Technology Management, GPA 3.7, Feb 2014

Bachelor of Science, Information Systems Technology Management, GPA 3.7 Dec 2011

CERRITOS COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Cerritos California

Associates in Science, Business Administration, GPA 3.88 Dec 2020

<u>Certifications</u>: CompTIA CySA+, CompTIA Security+, CompTIA Network+, CompTIA A+, Microsoft 365 Certified: Modern Desktop Administrator Associate Certification, ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

<u>Selected Additional Training:</u> Operating Systems Technologies & The Networking Environment; Installing, Configuring & Optimizing Computers; Managing Files and Folders; Devices in Microsoft Windows; Phase I/II MS SharePoint Server; Components, Printers, Networks and Safety; Fundamentals of Internet Explorer; Installing, Configuring and Optimizing Computers; Managing Files, Folders & Devices in Windows; Operating System Technologies & the Networking Environment; System Reliability & the Desktop Windows; Managing Hardware, Disks, and Logical Devices; Advanced; Remedy; Software and Web Based Configuration Administrator; Defense Messaging System;

Hardware: Printers, Fax, Copier, Digital Senders, Laptops, Desktops

<u>Selected Awards:</u> Army Commendation Medal, Air Force Achievement Medal, Army Achievement Medal, Numerous Letters of Appreciations from Wing Commanders, Class Commander U.S. Air Force Airmen Leadership School

Clearance: Active DoD & DOS USA Secret Clearance expires May 30, 2024

Military: Staff Sergeant (E-5), U.S. Air Force (Honorable Discharge, January 2011)